Jonathan Trosclair

1804 Old Schuylkill Road, Spring City, PA, 19475 | ijtrosclair@bellsouth.net | 1-337-412-3602

Summary

Enthusiastic and self-motivated individual passionate about language and helping others meet their goals. I am a native English speaker with nearly two years of experience teaching English as a second language. I also have a Bachelor's in English, and continue to pursue a passion for language by reading and writing creatively. In 2012 I won the Judge Felix J. Voorhies Award for creative writing. Over the past ten years I've worked in many different service capacities, including education, public service, and direct support service. I manage my own work schedule currently so self-motivation and punctuality are some of my strong points.

Education

Bachelor's in English

University of Louisiana at Lafayette 2010 - 2014

High School Diploma

Carencro High School 2006 - 2010

TESOL Certification (120 hours) 2018

International Open Academy

Work Experience

ESL Instructor VIPKid/Cambly

July 2018 - Present

Online teacher for intermediate level students learning the English language. Job duties include active engagement, adapting to individual student needs, time-management, scheduling classes, and understanding technical components of online teaching.

Direct Support Professional

WellLife Network

June 2018 - November 2018

Job duties include helping clients through basic aspects of daily life, from communication, to money management, to socialization. Patience and willingness to give individual attention are necessary skills for this work, alongside the ability to observe and adapt to specific needs of the clients.

Direct Support Professional

Alternative Services Oregon Inc.

July 2017 - June 2018

Job duties were largely identical as at WellLife network.

Library Technical Assistant

Lafayette Consolidated Government

June 2016 - July 2017

Engaging with the public in an alert and friendly manner to assist in the locating and checkout of library materials. Resolving account issues, helping disabled patrons with fax/copier services. Receiving packages and taking incoming phone calls.

Film Columnist

Vermilion Newspaper, ULL

June 2014 - December 2014

Writing critically about many aspects of film and cinema on a weekly basis. Remote communication with editors and firm grasp on the written English language were required.

Head Delivery Driver

Sherwin Williams

August 2013 - June 2016

Largely self-supervised delivery job. Responsibilities included meeting deadlines in a timely manner, planning efficient routes, and communicating remotely with the Sherwin Williams Dispatch via text and phone.

Cashier/Bartender

Daiquiri Depot

June 2012 - August 2013

Duties included taking orders, prepping fruit and bulk mixtures, assuring sanitary food conditions, and maintaining customer happiness.

Prep-cook/Pizza Oven Line Cook

Deano's Pizza

September 2011 - June 2012

Duties included prepping food for specials and regular dishes throughout the week. Following recipes and quick completion were key. Working the oven required management of multiple orders and pull times to assure that the food was hot when the order went out. Using high quality ingredients to make delicious meals was the top priority.